<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Martin Sitar</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/</link><description>Recent content on Martin Sitar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martinsitar.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prose</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/prose/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 11:10:36 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/prose/</guid><description>A Test with Tailwind Prose Classes With the new @tailwindcss/typography module I can add prose modifiers that will render to the output HTML. This allows you to style HTML tags individually with i.e. prose-h*:text-color-*00
this is a H1 header this is a H2 header this is a H3 header this is a H4 header You can change link colors too and define hover with prose prose-a:text-pink-700 hover:prose-a:text-cyan-700 - example: gohugo.io</description></item><item><title>Dive weekend - PADI Rescue Diver Certification.</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/post/rescuediver/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/post/rescuediver/</guid><description>I got my Open Water SCUBA certification when I was 15 years old. Since then I’ve been lucky to have many opportunities to dive, and slowly taken additional courses. This past fall I completed my PADI Rescue Diver certification. It was the most fun and rewarding SCUBA course I’ve taken so far.
—&amp;ndash;
The in-water training took place over 2 days in the middle of September at a quarry west of Kitchener.</description></item><item><title>Overlap</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/post/overlap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/post/overlap/</guid><description>Overlap lets you compare time zones across multiple locations and quickly find a time that&amp;rsquo;s reasonable in everyone&amp;rsquo;s workday. For me this comes in handy when I&amp;rsquo;m working with colleagues in other time zones, and especially when setting up interviews with users on the other side of the world.
Timezone scrolling Once you add the locations you need, scrolling right or left moves forward or backward in time across all of them simultaneously.</description></item><item><title>Highlighted</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/post/highlighted/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/post/highlighted/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever read a book that&amp;rsquo;s full of things want to remember you probably marked up pages in the book itself or took notes elsewhere. Highlighted is a handy little app that lets you easily capture all the important snippets of text you&amp;rsquo;d ever want, and makes them a breeze to find later on. Here are some of my favourite details.
Modal views Modal views present content in a separate mode from the user&amp;rsquo;s current context (more on that here).</description></item><item><title>Duolingo</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/post/duolingo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/post/duolingo/</guid><description>Duolingo is an amazing little app that helps you learn a new language with short, bite sized lessons you can do literally anywhere. The illustration style, clever copy, and fun UI make learning a new language enjoyable, and feel like something you can conquer. This app features refreshing visuals and interesting patterns, breaking the mold in a few areas. Here are some of my favourite details.
Emotion The designers did a great job of bringing emotion into the experience.</description></item><item><title>My favourite tools for sketching.</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/post/sketching-ux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/post/sketching-ux/</guid><description>Sketching concepts and ideas is a big part of my design process. It’s how I begin to visualize ways to solve a problem and quickly iterate through ideas. Sketching is imperfect and prevents you from getting caught up in too many details. I find there’s something special and freeing about exploring ideas in this way.
Paper + Pencil You don’t need fancy tools. My go-to’s are typically whatever pen or pencil I have on hand.</description></item><item><title>Quibi</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/post/quibi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/post/quibi/</guid><description>Quibi is a video streaming platform with a unique spin on short format, mobile-phone-only content. As the number of streaming platforms seems to grow almost daily, I decided to give Quibi a shot and found a few clever and interesting design patterns. I also discovered that recoding my iPhone screen while watching a video did not work, and resulted in a blank screen (which makes total sense) so I resorted to screenshots in those situations.</description></item><item><title>MinimaList</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/post/minimalist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/post/minimalist/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never been one to make to-do lists. I jot down thoughts in a notebook, and over the years when I needed a list I&amp;rsquo;ve relied on the Notes app in iOS. It&amp;rsquo;s straightforward, comes bundled with my phone and has done the job. In the past few months my work and personal life got quite busy and I found myself frustrated with Notes. I wanted a free, dead simple to-do app where I could file away the little tasks I was keeping in my head all day.</description></item><item><title>Tempo</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/post/tempo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/post/tempo/</guid><description>Tempo is an email client that helps you focus by letting you sort through email in batches rather than a constant stream of interruptions. This app is full of delightful animations and clever interactions that make it truly enjoyable to use. There are so many great things to cover you&amp;rsquo;ll have to try it out to experience them all, here are the ones I feel are worth calling out.
Workspace The workspace is your default landing page each time you launch Tempo.</description></item><item><title>Peloton</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/post/peloton/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/post/peloton/</guid><description>The Peloton is a stunning product, and I was as interested in the experience of using the application as I was in the bike itself. Having now taken over 30 classes I can honestly say it does a fantastic job of combining the physical aspects of taking a spin class with data rich performance tracking we&amp;rsquo;ve come to expect from our connected devices, plus the added benefit of extreme convenience. The designers put a lot of thought into making the experience enjoyable, meaningful and social in a way that’s different from typical home gym equipment.</description></item><item><title>Disney Plus</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/post/disneyplus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/post/disneyplus/</guid><description>Disney Plus was a huge success in terms of sign-ups when it launched on Nov 12. In just 24 hours it amassed over 10 million subscribers, and over 3.2 million app downloads. Having now been a month since the launch, they’ve ironed out initial glitches and started adding features, like continue watching. Overall it feels simple and approachable. One area that still falls short is the navigation and way-finding experience. Inconsistency in patterns and some navigation oversight add friction to the experience, lowering quality, and would benefit from some additional consideration.</description></item><item><title>Disney Plus</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/post/test/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/post/test/</guid><description>Disney Plus was a huge success in terms of sign-ups when it launched on Nov 12. In just 24 hours it amassed over 10 million subscribers, and over 3.2 million app downloads. Having now been a month since the launch, they’ve ironed out initial glitches and started adding features, like continue watching. Overall it feels simple and approachable. One area that still falls short is the navigation and way-finding experience. Inconsistency in patterns and some navigation oversight add friction to the experience, lowering quality, and would benefit from some additional consideration.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://martinsitar.com/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/readme/</guid><description>Hugo &amp;amp; Tailwind-3.0 A barebone Hugo &amp;amp; Tailwind CSS 3.0 starter kit
Download and install in VS Code
To start developing: npm run start
To generate the site HTML: npm run build
npm run start will run two command parallel: npx tailwindcss -i ./assets/css/main.css -o ./assets/css/style.css &amp;ndash;watch
and hugo server
Note: When you start npm run start a style.css must exist - or you get an error! Just do a Ctrl+C and run npm run start - even though you got an error but a style was written anyway and 2nd time round it should start fine.</description></item><item><title>Work</title><link>https://martinsitar.com/work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinsitar.com/work/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>