<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2020/04 on Martin Sitar</title>
    <link>https://martinsitar.netlify.app/archives/2020/04/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2020/04 on Martin Sitar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://martinsitar.netlify.app/archives/2020/04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Duolingo</title>
      <link>https://martinsitar.netlify.app/post/duolingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinsitar.netlify.app/post/duolingo/</guid>
      <description>Duolingo is an amazing little app that helps you learn a new language with short, bite sized lessons you can do literally anywhere. The illustration style, clever copy, and fun UI make learning a new language enjoyable, and feel like something you can conquer. This app features refreshing visuals and interesting patterns, breaking the mold in a few areas. Here are some of my favourite details.
Emotion The designers did a great job of bringing emotion into the experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favourite tools for sketching.</title>
      <link>https://martinsitar.netlify.app/post/sketching-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinsitar.netlify.app/post/sketching-ux/</guid>
      <description>Sketching concepts and ideas is a big part of my design process. It’s how I begin to visualize ways to solve a problem and quickly iterate through ideas. Sketching is imperfect and prevents you from getting caught up in too many details. I find there’s something special and freeing about exploring ideas in this way.
Paper + Pencil You don’t need fancy tools. My go-to’s are typically whatever pen or pencil I have on hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quibi</title>
      <link>https://martinsitar.netlify.app/post/quibi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://martinsitar.netlify.app/post/quibi/</guid>
      <description>Quibi is a video streaming platform with a unique spin on short format, mobile-phone-only content. As the number of streaming platforms seems to grow almost daily, I decided to give Quibi a shot and found a few clever and interesting design patterns. I also discovered that recoding my iPhone screen while watching a video did not work, and resulted in a blank screen (which makes total sense) so I resorted to screenshots in those situations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
